The hallucination thing is a lot of
people don't necessarily understand what
is likely to lead to that scenario. And
that's one of the reasons why people get
misled by like one shot examples of make
me a to-do list app, but real work isn't
like that. It's like I've got a very
specific internal library that you've
never seen before, you've never been
trained on, and I need you to get these
specific details right. Are good
engineering practices needed for agent
development? They're certainly
beneficial. And one of the things that
the Dora report found in 2025 was that
teams with high levels of development
maturity went faster when they
introduced agentic coding. Teams with
low levels of maturity went slower. I
can think of some SAS providers that
I've worked with who've had no
competitors for 20 years. In the last 6
months, two have popped up replicating
their feature set entirely using agentic
coding. So, there's a chance that you
will fall behind if you do not stay on
top of this stuff. What three tips would
you give an organization who wants to
roll out agentic software development
across their company?
Firstly,
>> [music]
[music]
>> Back in November, we hosted the first
ever in-person AI [clears throat] Native
DevCon in New York. This June 1st and
2nd, we're bringing it to London. It's 2
days built for AI native developers and
engineering teams. One day full of
hands-on workshops and one day full of
practical talks on agent skills, context
engineering, agent orchestration and
enablement platforms, [music]
and how teams are actually shipping AI
in production.
Join us at The Brewery in London near
the Barbican for all of that plus
networking, [music] parties, giveaways,
and a room full of people building the
future of AI native development. You can
also join us from anywhere in the world
via the live stream.
As you're listening to this podcast, you
get 30% off your ticket with code pod30.
Just head to ainativedevcon.io
and we'll see you in London.
In this episode, we're going to be
asking the big questions. What are the
hidden pitfalls that you don't even know
might be ruining your chances of success
with agentic development? And what are
the most important factors that a
developer needs to know about in using
agentic coding tools as well as rolling
it out across your organization. As I
mentioned, joining me on this journey is
Daniel Jones. Daniel, tell us a little
bit about what Re-Sync do. So, Re-Sync
is a consultancy in North Europe, and we
help people with AI native
transformation, whatever that means. And
it's a thing that is kind of emerging as
the state of technology evolves. We kind
of help people with across three threads
really. One is agentic coding, so using
AI in the software development process
to increase productivity.
Another is helping people build things
that leverage AI, so maybe where your
product has some ML features in or
you're building agents. And then the
third string of that is helping the
non-software parts of the business. So,
accounts, marketing, how can we
introduce agents or workflows that make
them more productive? So, looking at AI
AI nativity AI nativeness across all of
those different strands.
>> the AI nativity. We should definitely
celebrate that once a year. So, so
Daniel, you work with a lot of large
companies, enterprises, talking about AI
adoption and how those companies can can
best
take on and roll out agentic development
across large numbers of teams. Today,
we're going to be talking about some of
the advantages that can bring, but
really talking about some of the
pitfalls that people very often fall
into when trying to adopt, and some of
the best practices that we can add in.
So, why don't we kick off by talking
about
you know, people having good engineering
practices to start off with, and where
the pain exists whereby if someone
doesn't have a good engineering practice
and they use agentic development, where
that pain could be exacerbated. So, are
good engineering practices needed for
agent development? They're certainly
beneficial. And one of the things that
the Dora report found in 2025 was that
teams with high levels of development
maturity went faster when they
introduced agentic coding. Teams with
low levels of maturity went slower. And
this makes perfect sense when you look
at it through the lens of the theory of
constraints. You know, if you take one
part of system, speed it up massively,
then you're going to create bottlenecks
on either side. The interesting
challenge there is that we don't know
where exactly that tipping point is. So,
we're not sure how good you need to be
in order for things to get better or how
bad things need to be for it's to be
throwing petrol on a dumpster fire. And
when we talk about how good, what does
good look like? Is it is it
the documentation that needs to be
exist? Is it just people following
good workflow practices? What does good
mean? So, good can be measured in a
number of dimensions, and there are
quite a few. So, we've got things like
test coverage. We've got things like
alignment on what good looks like for
you know, the coding standards. We've
got things like the size of batches that
they're working on, like how big and
well detailed are their stories.
Um
We've got things like the path to
production, like what is their lead time
to production? Can they get changes out
quickly? Because if coding agents can
chuck out commit after commit minute
after minute, but it takes 3 days to get
anything into production, which is quite
optimistic for some enterprises, then
the tip of the branch is going to moved
on miles and you're going to end up with
loads of merge conflicts when something
goes wrong in CI. So, there's quite a
lot that really would be considered just
general good practice from the the last
10-20 years of software development that
that needs to be considered just because
everything goes much faster now. So,
having those good pipelines, those good
workflows, it enables that speed so that
you don't just have one massively sped
up component which is the actual deliver
the actual build of the the code.
And it's pointless having that if the
rest of it's just going to
you know, take time.
Tests, you mentioned tests.
Why are tests so important in an in a
true agentic development? So, tests are
important for
for one reason, but there's there's some
nuance here. And maybe we can get into
the ways that maybe some types of tests
are less important or at least less
important to humans.
First and foremost, if you don't have
good test coverage in your software,
then how is an agent going to know that
it's broken something? And really one of
the
things that people who are new to
agentic coding need to realize and often
kind of miss is that your agent needs to
be able to perceive something. If it
can't perceive a problem, then it can't
possibly react to it. So, whenever
you're getting frustrated with coding
agents, you need to consider like could
it have known better? Did it have the
information to know that it was doing
the wrong thing? And so, if your agent
keeps on breaking your software, well,
did it get fast feedback from a failing
test suite? If you've got low test
coverage, then it's quite likely that it
could break a whole bunch of things and
be absolutely none the wiser. And that's
not really the agent's fault because you
haven't given it the information or the
ability to perceive the fact that it's
making a mistake. And is it actually the
test runs that inform the agent, yes,
this is broken because the test failed,
or is it actually the agent using the
test cases as context almost to
understand actually this is this is
expected behavior. This is kind of what
we intend the application to do? That's
a really good point, and it is both.
Certainly the failing tests, like if
your agent is
well-mannered enough to actually run the
tests all the time, then it should
figure out that it's done something
wrong. But using the tests as
documentation and and guidance of what
is expected is quite important. I think
that
and this kind of brings me to I
mentioned nuance earlier of maybe unit
tests aren't for humans anymore. Maybe
those are too low level. Like if unit
tests help the agent figure out where
it's broken something, great. Okay, you
know, agent go go and write as many unit
tests as you like. But acceptance tests,
kind of outside-in acceptance tests that
define what a user should be able to do
with the system, those are important for
your like ultimate kind of safety
barrier of this is what I need it to do,
but also that guidance that you talked
about of this is the expected behavior.
This is what it needs to do. These are
the features that we want to have
regardless of whether they work or not.
This is what it is supposed to do. Um
and that kind of then bleeds into things
like spectrum development and where is
the source of truth? Is it the tests or
is it the spec? But these are all things
that going back to the previous point
about the last decade or two of good
software practice,
things like behavior-driven development,
you know, a good BDD test suite should
have been describing what the what the
software does at a kind of human
accessible level anyway. So, if you've
got that kind of thing in your code
base, then agents will be able to work
with it better. And it makes sense
really because if if if we as a
developer are turning more into intent
machines where we describe and define
the intent that we expect, and it's
actually the agent's responsibility to
to effectively generate that
implementation that describes the
behavior we we we ask for, the tests we
care about should be to validate the
intent that we're asking for. Whereas,
it should be the agent's responsibility
to create the unit test because they're
creating the implementation. So, it'll
be weird for us not to care as much
about the code, but then to care about
the unit tests for that code. It's nice
to kind of keep both test and intent or
generation levels the same.
What about
typical development hygiene, let's call
it? So, things like version control,
those types of things. Is that as
important with organizations doing
agentic development? Absolutely. Version
control in particular
is critical to
making good use of agents because sooner
or later your agent is going to do
something that you don't want it to.
It's going to commit a binary into Git
and then you're only going to notice
like four or five commits later and
you're going to want to remove that. So,
if folks aren't able to do things like
interactive rebasing, which you know, to
be fair, can be a little bit fiddly and
I found a little bit mind-bending when I
first learned how to do that, um then
you're going to end up with quite a
messy code base that will mislead humans
and it will mislead agents.
Another thing to consider when it comes
to version control is that
commits and branches are are cheap,
right? They're they're they're next to
free. They're they add very little
overhead. So, making lots of small
commits, which again, is like people
would argue, or I would certainly argue
it is good development practice anyway.
Maybe making even smaller, more frequent
commits is better because then you can
throw away the work that your agent's
done. And
when it comes to behavior change, a lot
of adopting agentic coding is not just
knowing how the tools work and gaining
new knowledge. It's unlearning old
habits.
>> Yes. So, being happy to throw away some
work that an agent has done because
you've got plenty of commits that you
can go back to. It's you're going to be
quicker throwing away something that an
agent did um and then starting again
than you would have done, you know,
typing on the keyboard yourself like it
was, you know, yeah, 2022 or something.
>> agents aren't precious.
They code, they don't care about
throwing that code away, right?
>> Exactly, yeah. I I often I say to people
that you should imagine you are the
worst software manager
possible. Um you know, insist that you
treat your agent a bit like a junior or
a member of staff that you really hate
and want to demoralize. Like, throw away
its work. Get three of them to work on
the same thing at the same time and only
have one of them have their work used.
Like, those those patterns actually make
you kind of more productive even if when
our AI overlords look back through our
chat history in 20 years time,
we're all going to be in trouble.
>> It's always good just to add in the odd
I respect you
>> [laughter]
>> or, you know, I very much appreciate
because, you know, we're not always
going to be top of the pecking order,
I'm not sure.
So, version let's talk continue talking
a little bit about version control. Who
should decide about the commits? Is this
something that we just, you know, maybe
as a hook to an agent or something which
we just say, "Look, after every
reasonable amount of code change,
whatever that is,
I want you to make sure you commit into
into a Git repo or something like that."
Who decides? I think that is a key
indicator of how psychologically
comfortable people are on their journey
to adopt agentic coding. And certainly
to start off,
I think folks are much more comfortable
making commits themselves. Like, ask
your agent to go and do a load of stuff.
I'm going to read the code. I'm going to
validate it and then I'm going to commit
it. As you build confidence and build
competence with things like spectrum
development, it becomes more acceptable
to to people psychologically. So, I'm
I'm going to let the the agent do the
committing here. Anytime that we
introduce a human having to take an
action, like we slow things down by, you
know, a several orders of magnitude. So,
if your agent is sat there going,
"I'm done. Do you want to commit this?"
and your your attention is elsewhere,
then it's making way less progress than
if you let it do that. Yeah. Um but then
there need to be some kind of guardrails
around that and
making sure that it's not just
steamrolling and definitely not doing
any force pushing. It it yes. It's funny
actually because
when I first started
you know, building with agentic coding
agents, uh
I did manual commit exactly the same. I
did manual commits and actually I was so
fast,
I actually realized, "Oh crap, I should
have commit I should have committed some
of this, you know, a long time ago." The
one thing I do love now, I always let my
agents commit for me as they as they as
they feel like changes are being made.
Uh the nice thing about that is you
actually when you go back, you can you
can dissect commits and you can go back
to a certain point very very easily
because it actually commits pretty
often. And like you say, it's free, it's
it's very very cheap to to to do these
commits. It makes makes software
development going back retrospectively
even much much nicer. You mentioned a
little bit about safety
when obviously there's a there's a YOLO
mode
which when we do want to increase that,
you know, the autonomy of coding agents,
we do want it to just go away and do
some stuff without constantly asking
like a child, "Can I do this? Can I do
this?"
Um what what do we need to think about
from a safety point of view,
particularly from an enterprise, that
it's not going to run havoc on our
nation? Yeah, I mean, enterprises are
extremely sensitive to this kind of
stuff. And one of the the points that
was providing much more friction than I
realized
was the use of containerization and
people's level of maturity with that.
Having come from a kind of cloud-native
background where we were deploying
things in Kubernetes and containerizing
all the things, I kind of took it for
granted that everybody would be familiar
with things like Docker and Kalima and,
you know, alternatives. Um turns out a
lot of enterprise developers aren't and
a lot of enterprises aren't necessarily
set up for people to be able to run
things in containers on their
development machines.
And if you don't, then you've got this
situation where people can be running
coding agents with dangerously skip
permissions natively on their host and
I'm pretty sure those people are going
to go to hell if they keep doing that.
Um so, running things inside containers
is definitely the way to go because then
you can you can let it off the reins and
um you don't need to be there to
constantly say, "Yes, you can do that.
Yes, you can run LS. Yes, you can cat
that file." Um
and I was optimistic about dev
containers. Mhm. So, this kind of open
standard that came out of Microsoft and
VS Code supports where you pop some
config in a directory and VS Code will
detect that that config is there and
then it will relaunch itself inside a
container. Nice. Um that's all great. Um
but the UX, like the the config is it it
fits into a sweet spot of hallucination
that maybe we're going to talk about in
a bit where it's recent and it's not
super popular, but it's popular enough
that agents tend to hallucinate the
config, which is super frustrating. Um
so, dev containers are a nice solution
to that, but maybe not quite mature
enough. And I've certainly seen
enterprise developers struggle with that
and spend hours, if not weeks, kind of
fine-tuning their
their dev container config and not being
able to move forward and make progress.
So, that that whole like
containerization thing, it's like MCP as
well. Like, I understand why it's this
way, but it would be lovely if they
would like all MCP servers were run like
all the standard IO ones were running
containers by default. Like, we've had
Docker for quite a long time. It would
be nice if everything was just secure
out of the box. And I was chatting with
Oleg Slav, actually, a former colleague
of mine
who works for Docker, a developer
advocate at Docker, and and I was
chatting with him about Docker sandboxes
and they seemed like ideal for this
exactly this type of thing.
And I think enterprises are really going
to want their developers to actually
start developing in this. When we talk
about the setup cost though, is it easy
to to develop in a sandbox compared to
obviously if you, you know, as a
developer I just want to go to a
terminal, kick off Claude and I can just
play, use my local resources and things
like that. How much is there if we're
doing this in a container? It's not
[snorts] massively
massively problematic or massively
burdensome in my opinion. And I think
one of the things about enterprise
developers is that they're often under a
lot of pressure to deliver features.
It's features, features, features and
they don't necessarily have the time to
invest in trying out different tools and
different ways of working.
And so, if you're in that environment
where you're not given freedom and space
to explore new things regularly and
you're of the mindset like, "I learn one
thing a year. I get sent on a course. My
company pays for it. I'll get a
certificate at the end and then I've
learned a thing." then it can be quite
uncomfortable to be using new tools like
containerization, dev
containers, to be using maybe a
different terminal emulator if you're
used to using an IDE, like
a big full-fat kind of graphical IDE and
then somebody's saying, "Oh okay, spin
up something in a terminal emulator and
then you're going to need to
authenticate with Claude code, but then
there's line breaks in the URL and you
can't redirect back to the port on
localhost cuz it's inside a container
and it's not exposing that port and then
you need to copy and paste tokens."
Those little bits of friction
definitely put people off.
>> Yeah. And it's something that's worth
considering
of guiding people through those just
because you don't want people to bounce
off before they've got to see the wonder
of like how productive these tools can
be.
>> Yeah. Yeah, absolutely. And really, I
think
it's the dangerously skip permissions,
the YOLO flag of I'm just going to let
Claude or whatever uh agent you're using
go off and do whatever it wants, whereby
those are the instances that actually
you really really need it in a container
because at least in the other instances,
you still get that choice of saying,
"Yes, I'm happy for you to do this." or
no, no, no, we need to have access to
that. That's fine. You mentioned
spec-driven development a little bit.
And actually I think I think that
providing it with the with the right
intent, providing it with the right
instructions,
um is very very important. We can do
that in a number of ways. We maybe talk
about skills and context in a little
bit. But when we actually talk about the
task that is required, and I guess
previously we would relate this to like
a user story or something like that. Um
how important is it to provide an overly
verbose or a concise user story? What
are the important things that we need to
add?
The
story that you can provide your agent
and the the the unit of work that you
provide to it is uh
hugely important in the level of detail
provided. And something that I think
we're exposing as we get agents more and
more into the mix is the amount of
knowledge in the head that is required
or the amount of knowledge in the head
that
we all take for granted when we're doing
software development. So, Donald Norman
in the psychology of everyday things, uh
book was renamed the design of everyday
things.
Talked about knowledge in the head and
knowledge in the world. Knowledge in the
world is discoverable. It's written down
somewhere. So, you know, having your
coding standards on Confluence or
something like that where maybe an agent
could get to it.
Knowledge in the world would be a
well-written story with acceptance
criteria so you could write test from
it.
Knowledge in the head would be, well, I
spoke to my product manager last week
and I know how they want this to be
implemented, but it's not written down
anywhere.
So,
if you are missing that kind of
information and there's lots of human
context required or you're used to
having that and just going, "Oh, I'm
just going to ask on Slack for
clarification on that." That's a really
bad spot for agents to be in and they're
not going to be able to produce results
that you want. They're not going to be
able to implement things without making
stuff up or asking a whole bunch of
questions. So, having a decent level of
specificity there is important. And this
is where
So, with one of the organizations that
I've been working with, we've asked them
to connect their coding agents up to the
Atlassian MCP server and then start
critiquing stories which the product
managers are maybe, you know,
raising an eyebrow at, but it's putting
back pressure on product on how
well-specced are these things.
And that's not necessarily because
product is doing a bad job, it's just
they used to having a much more informal
relationship. And something that I've
seen in quite a few organizations is you
speed up the software development part
and that puts pressure on product almost
immediately. And they're like, "Blimey,
we haven't got enough stuff figured out.
We can't keep the the agents well-fed.
We're going to need to massively speed
up what we're doing here and also
we're just so used to as humans maybe
not going into all the tedious detail we
need to because if somebody doesn't
understand then they can come and ask us
rather than
meticulously writing out every single
detail.
I'm going to talk
I want to kind of like switch a little
bit now and talk about the tools people
will will aim to use for a lot of these
things. In the past
it's been very much a discovery kind of
thing and and developers have been
playing with as many tools as they can
just to try and get used to AI and and,
you know, switch mindset into an I can
do this with AI approach.
What do we What do you see
from a
organization and industry point of view
of how companies are trying to adopt a
range of tools or focusing on specific
tools?
2025 was definitely the year of tech
leaders going, "I'm going to let people
use what they want and, you know, I'm
encouraging them to try stuff out and
we've got somebody over here using
GitHub Copilot, somebody over there
using Claude Code."
And I think part of that
came from lack of knowledge and comfort
from tech leaders kind of being like,
"There's so much to keep up track of. I
don't know what the latest thing is and
I don't want to like, you know,
bet on any one horse cuz I'm not sure."
And then also a fear of if I say we're
going to use this tool, not only might
it not be the right one, but it might be
that developers don't like it and then
they're going to push back because
they've got a lot of pride in their job
and the sense of identity from it. So,
2025 was a lot of kind of soft touch,
organic, disorganized trialing of
things.
I think over Christmas
Anthropic did a great thing for for
their marketing of
giving people free usage over Christmas.
A lot of bored CTOs and VPs of
engineering trying out Claude Code and
going, "Wow, this really works." So,
2026 has definitely seen a shift in
people wanting to be much more
structured of like, "Okay, we need seen
what's possible now. We need to roll
this out across the the department,
across the team, across the
organization." And
yeah, we're we're seeing folks try to
standardize on tools.
And I think there's still quite a
a lot of anxiety over what is the right
tool to pick from an enterprise and
organizational level. A lot of it sadly
is driven by licensing and the logistics
of how we pay for these things.
You know, there's some speculation at
the moment as to whether
Claude Code licenses are the
subscriptions are going to get revoked
for enterprise usage. I've seen some
chatter about that.
But, you know, if you've got 1,000
developers and each of them need to
expense
an Anthropic subscription every month,
that's a huge amount of overhead as
opposed having an enterprise agreement.
So, we see quite a few people kind of
opting for GitHub Copilot
just because it's part of their GitHub
enterprise offering.
Whether that's the right choice for
every organization though is an entirely
different matter. Yeah. And is the is
the worst decision indecision here?
I think though there's a strong case for
that in that
often when people are faced with
transformative change,
they either jump in with both feet and
no plan. And we saw a lot of that in
2024 of like, "We need to do some AI.
What do we need to do?" "I don't know.
Just do some AI. Here's some [laughter]
budget."
And definitely saw that happening at
large financial institutions and, you
know, lo and behold, they didn't get any
return on investment.
Who would have seen that one coming? But
then there's the
alternative of we're going to wait until
this is settled a settled science and
we're not going to waste money getting
up to speed on this.
And the speed of change continues to
increase
as time goes on. So, holding off I don't
think is a viable solution. Having some
amount of budget, some amount of time,
some amount of slack in the system to
explore and trial things out is the most
sensible strategy because otherwise
there's a very
I don't want to fearmonger, but there's
a decent chance that you will get
outpaced by a startup who is embracing
these things. I can think of some SaaS
providers that I've worked with
who've had no competitors for 20 years.
In the last 6 months, two have popped up
replicating their feature set entirely.
And these are brand new startups who
presumably are using agentic coding to
just,
you know, replicate their software very
very quickly. There's a chance that you
will fall behind if you do not stay on
top of this stuff. And then if we do get
to a point where it's settled science,
like do you want to be starting from a
standstill? Because there are, you know,
approaches, things like managing context
windows. As far as we can see if models
carry on working the same way they do
and the architecture doesn't change
radically, then this is going to be an
underpinning constraint of all agentic
software development
going forward. Even if we end up with
software factories that build upon these
things, you need to understand the the
fundamentals underneath. That's a good
That's a good segue. Let's talk about
tips and I'd love to talk about tips
that you can give developers directly
and then we'll maybe talk about tips for
rollout across an organization. So, tips
for developers. And you talked about
context. Let's go deeper into that.
Context is you obviously, you know,
provide your messages to this is the
task I want you to do. Context is really
important. Now, whether that's
skills or instructions about how your
organization wants to develop software,
those types of things.
How much is the right amount of context?
So, looking at academic research,
certainly the No Leema paper from 2024
suggested above 30,000 tokens of context
reasoning ability drops off by about
15%. There is another paper, the name of
which escapes me, that was repeating
experiment in 2025
for
GPT-4.1 era models and found between
30,000 and 60,000 tokens again reasoning
capability drops off.
That's not very much. Like there have
been
Claude Code, you know, three releases a
day so things change all the time, but I
have certainly there have been points
where I've opened up Claude Code, no MCP
server installed, no Claude MD and it's
already using like 40,000 tokens just
for its system prompt.
So, it doesn't take much to tip your
model into the point where it's going to
get confused.
But one of the challenges with this is
the when I
was starting developing agentic coding
training for people, I I I
I I was on a video games website over
Christmas and gamers tend to hate
generative AI. They think it's going to
be the ruination of all things. I was
like, "I'm going to try and like educate
people about why it's not all bad." And
I mentioned in the comments on some
website, why why was I posting comments
on a website, that I was doing agentic
coding training and somebody posted very
snarky response like, "Duh, why do you
need to teach people how to use coding
agents? Like don't they just work?" And
I was like,
"You know what? That's that's actually
quite a good point. And because these
things just work,
it's not until you have problems that
you need to understand what's going on
underneath. And context windows and
context management is a good example of
that.
If you just use a coding agent and
everything's working fine, you don't
need to worry about context. And then,
you know, your conversation goes on a
bit and then it starts to fall apart and
you get more frustrated, but it's not
obvious that's because your context
window the amount of context that you're
using has gone over the effective limit
or that you've distracted it by talking
about too many things in one chat. So,
that is something that quite, you know,
clever engineers who are new to this,
it's not obvious. It's not immediate to
them. Yeah, and I always say like a
developer, they know when they're in the
Goldilocks zone of context whereby
they're like one-shotting prompts
because they they're giving enough
context for it to to have that
acceptable answer. They're not giving
too much context so that the
the agent gets confused. It's just
enough. How should a developer keep just
enough context? Is it something that
they should proactively monitor or
something they should react to if the
agent is going astray? I was certainly
of the opinion that people should be
proactively monitoring this and also
workflow habits of, you know, whenever
you're at a clean break clear your
context whenever you need to ask a
off-topic question and like my mind does
not stay in in one
train line for very long so I'm normally
thinking about three things at once like
use a different chat use a different app
like I use warp
a gentic terminal and if I need to ask
something Linux e command line e I'll do
it in warp if I'm doing something in
Claude code and I'm trying to build a
feature with Claude I'll try and keep
that on topic I need to research or go
to a web browser and use you know a chat
app like chat GPT or Gemini so splitting
up the conversations has the advantage
of not distracting the model with too
many concepts in one chat and not
extending the amount of context that
you're using so clearing your context
regularly not going off topic are things
that are valuable to do
Um
The other thing that kind of maybe
slightly different is not adding all of
the MCP servers
and not adding all of the instructions
for every possible eventuality of how to
write software into your agents guidance
or agents MD there was a paper that came
out of Zurich
a couple of weeks ago that showed that
adding stuff to your
agents MD will like reduce the quality
of outcomes by about 20% over and having
no instructions whatsoever And it's
interesting looking at things that have
been fashionable over the months as as
we all learn about this like you know I
remember certainly September time people
talking about put all the things in
agents MD every time it makes a mistake
stick something else in agents MD but
what you're doing there is you are
saying something that's largely
irrelevant most of the time in the hope
that it's relevant this time so that's
not a great thing to do then it was like
I'm going to add all the MCP servers for
every eventuality And that causes its
own problems like a lot of people don't
realize how tool calls work and the fact
the full menu of tools need to be
provided to the model on every single
prompt just in case it wants to use one
of them so skills and progressive
disclosure are a much kind of better
solution to this where
instead of sending the model all the
details about skill there's like a a
little summary and the model can ask for
more information if it wants to And and
let's talk about that cuz I think that's
really important there's a couple of
things here one is like the behavior
under the covers and the second is more
activation which is
a global problem today but something
that we expect to get better so
>> [snorts]
>> you talk about adding things into the
agents MD
anything that you add into the agent MD
file the agent will fully read it
doesn't necessarily mean it'll act upon
it but it will fully read when you add
an MCP
again there's a description there it
chooses when to activate it similar to a
skill I guess
a skill like you said there's a
description there it chooses when to use
that these are kind of more of the on
demand style approaches so if you if the
the LLM or agent feels like it needs to
learn more about this thing or feels
like it's doing something and it
triggers a skill as a result of wanting
to do development in a certain way or
wanting to write code to a to a style
guide it chooses to then use that skill
read that context etc. So the overhead
there is is very real if you have
hundreds of MCP servers hundreds of
skills it's going to get confused and
it's actually probably not going to pick
the skills you want it to
do you have experience or advice in
terms of not necessarily what the right
number of skills or MCP servers are
because it's it's very subjective but
what does what what advice would you
give to someone who is thinking about
adding yet another skill or yet another
MCP
to their environment I think add them
judiciously
maybe have loads that you rely on but
don't have certainly for MCP servers
don't have them all add added and
registered at the same time if you do
need registered at the same time then
maybe selectively filter out their tools
if your agent doesn't support that
natively then maybe you could use an MCP
gateway for that
for skills I think there's a slightly
less of a problem with that because the
progressive disclosure
but you might end up with multiple
skills have very similar descriptions
and then the model's not sure which one
it wants to ask for more information on
so yeah that that could be a problem and
I know
having spoken we I spoke to Amy Heineke
from Tessell who was talking about this
and some of the challenges that you
folks face in making sure that
you know the the things that you're
building get selected by the model and
it's it's a thorny problem so I gather
Activation generally
is is a thorny problem in terms of
making sure that the agent chooses the
right skill or the right you know the
right piece of context at the right time
and it's
it's definitely a a problem that exists
today I think it'll be less of a problem
as time goes on and as agents get more
used to using skills
but yeah it'd be interesting to see how
that how that turns out so
when we think about
a user a developer part of a team
building a certain part of you know
a project that is much much broader
um
when we think about context management
and replicating their environment to
share essentially the environment that
that developers environment with the
rest of that team what's the best way to
be able to replicate that that context
the context management from one
developer to another is that something
that should be more global stays with
the repository or is that something
which is
should be more
subjective to the developer how they
want to work
It's an interesting point and one of the
places where team dynamics and
the conflict avoidance that sometimes is
arguably necessary or allowed in large
teams to proliferate can kind of create
problems in that if you've got lots of
developers with different ways of doing
things then maybe in an the old world
pre agentic coding then that was
acceptable when you knew that you know
Rachel over there has her way of writing
code and Steve over there has his way um
[snorts]
but if you've got an agent going over
that code base and then it's being
confused by two different code styles
then that becomes more of a problem
Generally I would say that having things
as global as possible and consistent is
going to lead to better results and as
we move away from individual developers
having their own idiosyncratic styles
that they like to deferring more of the
implementation to agents does it matter
if the code's written the way that you
like it versus the way that I like it as
long as the agent is able to deliver
useful outcomes and features more
quickly
So trying to standardize
and make sure that these things are
available to agents when they need them
whether that is global and maybe you put
that
you know in in confluence or a wiki and
you
give your agent an MCP service so we can
access that um the the problem with that
is drift and when it changes then
you're probably better having that in
your code repository so you the guidance
is pinned to a particular version and as
that evolves it's clear you know
wikis are often where documentation goes
to die so
you know if you want stale and out of
the date information that's a good place
to put it so probably in the repository
would be the the main place to do that
and then when you get folks
having context and guidance that they're
keeping local to themselves
I can imagine that leading to problems
over if you've got conflicting
information and then you've got one
agent doing things one way on one
person's machine another you know those
are the kind of patterns that we've
generally throughout computing gone you
know this this is going to lead to bad
outcomes we want things done
consistently and universally across a
team or at least throughout a code base
Yeah probably worth mentioning Tessell
here as well actually cuz obviously
Tessell is that kind of like that
package manager for skills and context
so actually it does a lot of what you
mentioned there there's a lot of the
like the versioning of of skills and
context the ability to almost like have
a manifest file within the repository
that then pulls in the right context as
per pinned in the in the in the manifest
but but I think what you kind of like
mentioned is really interesting whereby
things like coding styles I've never
heard an agent argue whether it should
use spaces or tabs but there are things
that are still important the stack that
we use the the methodologies that we of
how we develop with you know test driven
development or
how we choose to develop is going to be
important more than the the the
cosmetics of the of the code I think
which is which is super important
you mentioned kind of like
hallucinations a little bit before as
well um do do you feel like how do you
how do you see
agents coding correctly
how do we use context to to maintain
accuracy So the hallucinations thing is
a lot of people don't necessarily
understand what is likely to lead to
that scenario and so in the training
that we provide we get people to do an
exercise with a really old model so GPT
3.1 where we can deliberately mislead it
and make it hallucinate things and it's
really quite interesting doing that if
you ask about Star Wars episode 10 like
the model goes no that's not a real film
so when you're talking about big
well-known concepts um then it it it can
detect lies
quite well like Phantom Menace not a
real film doesn't exist does it I would
probably say more about 7 8 and 9 let's
not go [laughter] there
still scarred
If I was to ask GPT 3.1 tell me about
the London thrash metal band Simon and
the Maples
then it would probably tell me there's
no such band If I asked that same model
tell me about the
thrash metal stroke hardcore band Simon
and the Maples. They were active in
Camden between 1997 and 1999.
Then it's much more likely to start
spewing out a bio. And we we did this
with the exercise about 50% of the time,
moving from a capital city to a
particular area and putting a date range
in. Where previously the model would
have said, "No, no such thing." It's
then like spewed out band bios, talked
about like the the breakup of the band
and who fell out with who and all that
kind of stuff. So, that's an example of
if you are adjacent to large concept
concepts and very specific, then you're
in the sweet spot of hallucination. And
also, if it's something that the model
is likely to have been adjacent to
something that the model is likely to
have been trained on. So, I had the
exact experience for what Tessell Tile
Registry
was made to solve. And though I had one
of the developers that I was training
talking about, "Ah, I was using the
latest version of some library and my
model was hallucinating.
Um it knew that it was a new version. It
wasn't giving me the old
API endpoints, but it was hallucinating
new ones that didn't exist." And I was
like, "I've got a thing for you."
>> [laughter]
>> Somebody has solved that problem. But
but it's very interesting because
typically those types of challenges or
problems, the the specifics that are
added by by the user or by the agent in
terms of I need to do these very
specific things, it's it's very
detailed. So, it's actually rife for
those types of hallucinations. Exactly.
And that's one of the reasons why people
get misled by like one-shot examples of,
"Ah, make me a to-do list app or make me
a Flappy Bird clone." And "Oh wow, this
is really great." But real work isn't
like that. It's like, "I've got a very
specific internal library that you've
never seen before, you've never been
trained on, and I need you to get these
specific details right." So, that
element of detail, and this is why I
think the band example is quite
illustrative because when you start
narrowing down to really specific
things, that seems to be when it's more
likely to hallucinate.
>> Yeah. Yeah, cuz we're mostly taught
around the Chelsea area anyway. So,
it's probably it's very easy to do. Um
So, we talk we've talked a little bit
about we've talked a lot about agents,
very little about LLMs. Um and actually
when we think about the hallucinations
and things like that, it's coming from
the LLM. Yeah. So, when we think about
the roles of each and how we select and
choose the tools,
um what should we be mindful of when
thinking about that? And I think that's
a really good point and a lot of people
new to the technology, and you know,
I've probably been
conflating the two because you you
interface with the agent. And then
really it's the model making decisions
about like which tool to use. The agent
itself is you know,
uh
not very smart. It doesn't have very
much logic in it. It can't do it. It's
just a loop
running around and the model is making
decisions.
And
one when folks are new to agentic coding
get into this, they don't necessarily
understand like what is the difference
between the agent's responsibilities and
the models. And so like when we're doing
training after we've done an exercise
with people, we go through on a
whiteboard like, "Okay, what did we just
do?" Um and then draw it up, draw up all
of the components, where they live, like
you know, where the tool definitions
are, how they get to the model, all that
kind of stuff, which helps cement it in
people's minds.
>> [snorts]
>> Folks that are coming into this new, and
there are a lot of them. Like in the
last couple of weeks, I know so many
senior engineers who have reached out to
me directly and been like, "I feel like
I'm falling behind. Like can you help me
get up to speed with this?"
And they
get up to speed really quickly. They
normally jump in with Claude Code or
something a terminal-based agent.
And they get using it and get it
productive, but still without knowing
what's under the hood.
And so folks end up kind of worrying
about which is the best agent to use.
And really
there are functional kind of differences
in terms of how large each of the system
prompts are and how many you like how
much of your context window, effective
context window that leaves you with. But
really it's more like personality.
You know, it's more like you know,
different brands of cola. You know,
they're all full of sugar and fizzy.
They just have slightly different spins
on them. And really
also the models, like if I use
the latest GPT and if I use Opus 4.6,
they're probably going to be roughly
equivalent in terms of what they can do.
If I switch from Opus to Haiku, then I'm
going to notice differences. But really
the different foundation frontier
models,
they're all roughly capable
and equivalent. So, people see the brand
names and they see the tools and they're
like, "Oh, well Codex is going to be
much better than Claude Code." What I
think is more important is ergonomics.
Like do they have the features that you
want that allow you to work in the way
that you want to without having to
sit there and babysit the agents.
Do they you know, support skills? Do
they have the the UX that you want? That
is productivity is more important than
correctness. Like the correctness is
something you don't have much control
over. Either the model's trained well or
it's not.
The
productivity that you get from having
the features that you want and the user
experience that you want combined with
the context management, that is a much
bigger determinant of whether you're
going to get useful outcomes rather than
you know, which model you're using
because they're all pretty you know, the
frontier labs are trying very hard to
keep up with each other. And it could
also be around the way you as a
developer ask your questions or provide
your requirements because the models are
going to pick up differently. The models
are going to have different activation,
ways of activating the the the skills
using the context. And so it may be and
this perhaps this is why there are so
many arguments as to which you know, who
gets the most out of which models and
agents because people are asking things
in a different way. So,
yeah, a lot of it could just be
you know, which agent actually works
best with the way you like to work, the
way you ask for things.
Hey everyone. Hope you're enjoying the
episode so [music] far. Our team is
working really hard behind the scenes to
bring you the best guests so we can have
the most informative conversations about
agentic development. Whether that's
talking about the latest tools, the most
efficient workflows, or defining best
practices. But for whatever reason, many
of you have yet to subscribe to the
channel. If you're enjoying the podcast
and want us to continue to bring you the
very best content, please do us a favor
and hit that subscribe button. It really
does make a difference and lets us
continue [music] to improve the quality
of our guests and build an even better
product for you.
All right, back to the episode. Yeah,
the one of the ways that agentic coding
is problematic here is because of the
non-determinism. It is a breeding ground
for superstition. And if you look back
through the kind of annals of
human-computer interaction and usability
engineering, then there are plenty of
examples where when people get in
like
non-consistent results. There's there's
a word for that.
Then intermittent incoherence.
Then they start to come up with
superstitions like, "Oh, it only works
when I click on this thing first before
doing the doing the doodah." Um
so yeah, folks can start getting all
these superstitions about which prompts
work and which ones don't, which is why
you know, the kind of work that Amy was
talking to me about about running Evals
on things is so important to try and get
some science into this. From my own
experience and working with the the
hundreds of developers that I have, the
the whole kind of prompt engineering
doesn't seem to be that important. Um
it's more about context management. And
as you say, how you communicate
requirements. The whole like how you
phrase the question or like if you give
it a persona, I don't see that making
too much of a difference even if it is
something that is quite
immediately engaging to humans of like
we like the idea. It's more about
framing the context, making sure the
right information is there, that the
agent has the ability to perceive when
it's doing the wrong thing, and whether
your requirements are coherent or not.
So, let's talk about the data cuz I
think that's an important piece. And
very often so much of so much of this
world is anecdotal in terms of ah yeah,
I think this skill works most of the
time. Let's leave it like that or you
know, essentially
going from gut feel of my experience
was. How do we bring data into that?
Maybe through skills or context as well.
Well, I gather that you folks have a It
was a loaded question. a skills package
manager where you're rating skills both
on how well written they are and how
effective they are, which you know, I
think is a hugely valuable thing because
So, yesterday I was doing something in
GoLang, I'll say I. Claude Code was
doing something in GoLang for me. And I
installed the Go Language Server plugin.
And I set it off running and I'm like,
"Is it even using this thing? Like I
don't I'm not paying attention. I'm
doing other stuff whilst it's trundling
away. Is it using Is this making any any
anything better?"
And having more scientific data on that,
I think
is incredibly valuable.
Maybe
going out to the far future, when we end
up with software factories, which is a
whole kind of separate topic of
conversation where humans are involved
much less.
>> [snorts]
>> I'm excited by that idea because
being able to run
requirements through a software factory
where you have multiple agents
collaborating and outputting finished
software for a given set of
requirements. Like if all of that is
under version control and has full
observability, then you can run like
methodological experiments in a way that
you can't do with a human team because
you can't get somebody to like pretend
they didn't just implement that story
and then try doing it a different way.
Whereas with software factories, we
might be able to do that and slowly
iterate and tweak prompts and tweak
skills and which skills are we using and
how are those skills written
to
be able to automatically start getting
ourselves to maximum productivity of
that software factory. But until we're
there, so little visibility for the end
user into what they're doing, when
they're activating skills, why, how well
those are working. And I think it's
something where the the kind of
magicness of agentic coding tools works
against the user. Like, it's great when
it just works, but actually we also need
to be able to see the you know the dials
and the readouts to figure out what's
going on. Totally. And I think there's a
there's a number of things that I find
very important here. We talked about
activation.
And a lot of the time with activation,
it's the way we write the skill. For
example,
Anthropic
delivered a whole bunch of best
practices of how to write skills, which
was added into a blog. And actually our
Tesla review skill
essentially uses LLM as a judge to to to
work out whether those best practices
have been adhered to. And I think from
the activation, realistically, the only
way to actually look back in hindsight
and say, "How good is my skill from an
activation point of view?"
is to look through the logs. And almost
like say,
"How many times should this skill have
been activated?" And how many times was
it activated? And and there's probably
an amount of work there that can that
can kind of look look through that and
provide that data.
And that's definitely one thing that
we're looking at here at Tesla. The the
the other thing I think is
what we call task evals within Tesla,
which is essentially run this with the
skill, run it without the skill, and
work out actually if you do use the
skill,
what benefit does it provide you? And
for me, as a
for writers of skills, for authors of
skills versus or context versus the
consumers, it it it shows you with data
where your skill can be improved. And
that for me, like whether it's 80% or
85% improvement with a skill,
you know, that that that to me is useful
information. It's a kind of like fuzzy
feel good. But for me, the value here is
for the author to go back and say, "I
can see what scenarios are failing. I
can see what scenarios actually my
context doesn't provide much value for
because it was getting it right
beforehand." And going back to the point
of overwhelming an agent with context,
if an agent does well out the box
already, does it need that context to
actually just tell it to do the same
thing the same way? It provides you that
data to
to enhance and iterate to to optimize
the skill that you're creating. Yeah,
and this is somewhere where I think from
an enterprise context, we're going to
see something new emerge. You know, in
the last 10 years, platform as a
product, platform engineering, providing
a deployment substrate to your engineers
was was hugely important. And you know,
people looked at developer experience
and that kind of stuff. But the kind of
experiment running that you were
describing there, that's something the
average enterprise developer doesn't
have the time to do. They're like, "Ah,
I'm going to do this story twice." Or
maybe they have the inclination of like,
"I'll run this once in one work tree
with a skill and once in another work
tree without a skill, and then I'll look
and evaluate that." They normally have
too much feature pressure.
So, I can imagine a world in which And
in fact, I see this happening in some
organizations, where there's like this
kind of like
it's it's not quite a platform team, but
like a DevEx AIA abstraction team, where
they are building they're working out
which are the right tools to use. And
and a much earlier, you mentioned about
the challenges of um
an enterprise managing which skills are
in use and that whole package management
thing that I know you folks are looking
at. I have absolutely seen CTOs talking
about that and asking the question very
directly of like, "How the hell do you
manage all of these skills?" Like, you
know, it's just scripts floating around,
moving between people's machines. Like,
we need this to be auditable, we need it
to be versions, we need to see what's
running where because we're regulated.
So, I can imagine that as these tools
start to get
more uptick, we're going to end up with
teams of people who are trying to
provide a sensible kind of base level of
abstraction for all the other developers
to stand upon. And and to work out which
is the right skill to use. Wow.
>> And do you think that's like a new role
in the
It feels like an extension of the
platform team, but perhaps not something
that the platform team has existing
skills around. Do you do you feel like
it will be a role that maybe lives in
the platform team?
Or do you see that as a completely
separate team?
I think it would be nice if platform
teams did that because
really, you know, platform teams have
tended to evolve out Well, I say evolve
out, evolve out of infrastructure teams.
But then typically, platform teams also
have this injection of a lot of
infrastructure teams were very kind of
ticket oriented, especially in the
enterprise like service now. Ticket
comes in, I do a thing, it goes out.
They're not building something for the
future that gets better every day. And
then you have this injection of like
product management and software
engineering. It's like, "No, we're going
to make durable solutions for this
rather than like doing toil and ticket
comes in, ticket goes out. We're going
to make a bit of automation to make sure
that we never have to do that ticket
again."
So, we've already seen like the
evolution from infrastructure teams to
platform teams and them introducing new
skill sets. I think it would be nice to
see the identity of a platform team
evolving into how can we support
developers with immediate future things
running locally in terms of agents and
the skills that they're using. Maybe the
platform team becomes the software
factory team in the longer term. And
when we think about rollout for a large
organization, do you see that rollout
coming from that platform team as they
essentially are the enablers, right?
Whether it's the developer experience,
the platform team, all of these groups
are enablers for larger enterprise
development teams.
Do do you see that rollout spawning from
that team?
Yes, in the sense that
like a customer that we're talking to at
the moment, they've got 12,300
developers. And so, rolling out a
consistent, sensible, auditable,
regulatory
safe set of agentic coding practices,
that's going to need coordination. And
that's going to need to come from
somewhere central. If you've got people
making up their own rules and ideas and
pulling in skills and plugins
willy-nilly across the organization,
that's going to lead to
Yes, auditing chaos. So, that will need
to be coming from a central place.
And
I see I'm just I'm I'm thinking of a
particular customer here where there's
a lot of people that were interested in
the path to production and platforms
were generally interested in tightening
feedback loops and value streams. We
haven't haven't talked about value
stream mapping at all, but that's a
hugely important part when you're trying
to adopt agentic coding practices is
working out how your software delivery
function works as a system and what's
going to happen if you speed up one
particular part of it.
But the kind of people that were
interested in things like DevOps and
platforms, they were always interested
in productivity, getting ideas into
production as quickly as possible so
then the product folks can learn, was
that the right thing to build? So, it's
a natural kind of progression for them
to be thinking about how can we speed up
other aspects of software delivery. What
three tips would you give a developer
who wants to be successful with agentic
coding?
One, get stuck in, start using
something.
Two, context management, make sure you
understand it. And three, perception,
make sure that your agents can perceive
what's going on so it can fix things.
With the
getting started, just pick a tool.
They're all much of a muchness, they're
all fairly similar. So, just get started
with one. Don't put this off until you
think it's going to be settled science
because everything is moving faster and
continuing to move forward.
With context management, it's not
obvious what's going on under the hood.
Clear your chats regularly. Make sure
that you stay on topic. Don't give the
model an excuse to be confused about
things. Don't add everything in the
kitchen sink into your agents MD because
it's just going to make things worse.
On the topic of perception,
if your agent lets you down or
frustrates you by breaking things in CI,
well, it needs to be able to see what's
going on in CI. So, add an MCP server so
it can check what's going on in the
latest build. Otherwise, you can't blame
it for when it breaks things. What three
tips would you give an organization who
wants to roll out agentic software
development across their company?
One, make sure that you're using a
mature team who are enthusiastic and
keen to adopt change. Two, they need to
be well aligned, have documented
definition of what good looks like. And
also three, they need to have good
product management behind them where
things are specific and well thought out
and there is a decent backlog of work to
act upon.
If you start off with a team that's
already enthusiastic and performing
well, they are more likely to go faster
and you'll have better results that you
can then repeat throughout the
organization. You've got the social
proof of when people are looking at
their peers of what has worked well and
they can be impressed by those results.
Folks need to be aligned around what
good looks like. If you've got different
ideas of what good code is, there's no
way an agent is going to be able to
consistently come up with
results that satisfy everybody. So, that
needs to be documented. Everybody needs
to be on board
on the same page of what good
engineering is. The product management
side is something that people often
forget. Things need to be well specified
so that agents can pick them up. As well
as being well specified, there needs to
be a decent backlog of work and a good
understanding that underpins that what
it is that needs building because as
soon as you get your developers going
faster, that backlog of stories is going
to run dry very quickly. And I've seen
that happen in quite a few
organizations. Yeah. Amazing. Awesome.
And as a final question, let's look a
little bit forward. And you kind of I
think you've already alluded to some of
this during the session.
But looking forward, how do you see the
future of agentic development
changing maybe the way we work as
individual developers, but also as a
workforce, as a as a company, the
organization?
The potential organizational change
could be massive in that And And there's
kind of incremental steps towards this
where engineers are starting to get more
encroachment on product turf by doing
spectrum development. You've got
products people starting to encroach on
the engineering space with the idea of
prototype as requirements. And those are
all kind of incremental. But I think the
big potential change here is software
factories. You're already hearing about
like hive mind startups where it's too
slow to write things down because
factories of multiple agents
collaborating can deliver software so
quickly that writing something down just
slows the whole system down. So when we
end up in that world and we're having
conversations with customers about this
does the world look like where you've
got one product engineer per value
stream. You don't have a two-pizza team
anymore. So many of the things about
good Agile software development might go
out the window there.
So if we can end up with software
factories, dark software factories where
no one's reading code, no one's writing
code, that reliably produce the right
thing, then the future of the industry
is going to look very different. But I
really hope we're going to end up with
much more bespoke usable software and an
abundance of it. A proliferation of
unique solutions for individual people
and teams where they don't have to wait
for a SaaS provider to 18 months ago,
"Can you please implement this feature?"
Like somebody can go and build it for
you on a small scale
almost immediately. And that, I think,
is cause for optimism. Daniel, it's been
absolutely wonderful and and very
insightful hearing hearing some of the
stories, hearing some of the advice, and
particularly the tips for people to to
really get going as a developer or as
someone who wants to roll out agentic
development more within their
organization. Super appreciate all your
advice, all your thoughts, and it's been
great having you on the episode. Cool.
Thank you very much. It's been a
pleasure being here. Thank you very
much, Daniel, and thank you very much
for listening. Tune in to the next
episode soon.